This video demonstrates how to assess neurovision and dispense glasses.
Wash your hands and don't pee pee.
You'll need a neurovision chart, pen and clinical notes, range
of reading glasses and a 40cm long piece of string.
Explain what you're going to do in gain consent.
Sit the patient comfortably in a well-lit place.
Use a string to make sure the chart is held at the correct 40cm distance.
Ask them to read down the chart with both eyes together.
Record the smallest line they can read comfortably.
If they cannot read the N8 line, then try with plus 1.5 diopter sphere glasses.
If they still can read N8, then use the next higher power, and so
on, until they can comfortably
read N8 text.
Make sure the glass is fiddle-k and the patient is happy with their appearance.